RUSS SALAKHUTDINOV:
Today I'm going
to talk about
multimodal AI agents,
and give you a little bit
of overview of what we've
been doing and some of the
work that's been happening
around that space.
It's a very exciting space.
I think that a lot of people are
thinking that the year 2025-2026
is going to be
the year of aging.
So we'll see a lot more
work coming out of academia
and industry in that space.
So when we think about
large language models,
we think a lot of
different innovations
that happened in
the last few years.
We see examples of in-context
learning, zero-shot learning.
You have very good
representations of text.
You have general long and
coherent text that these models
can generate, world knowledge.
And so amazing things
has been happening
in the space of large
language models, right?
But what I would like to
talk to you about today
is this notion of going beyond
just the language models.
So you can think of language
models as, given the question,
the language model can
generate the answer, instead,
we can try building
systems where--
that basically can automate
a lot of laborious tasks.
And a lot of productive tasks we
perform today on the computer,
potentially, as well as many
tasks that we perform on the web
could potentially
be automated, OK?
So, for example, how
many of you have tried
setting up AWS instance, right?
My students are basically saying
it's a really difficult process
to do.
The question is, couldn't you
have an agentic model that
goes and sets up AWS
instance for you,
so you can start running
your experiments.
Or wouldn't it be nice, and I
think the technology is getting
there a little bit at this point
is, create a set of PowerPoint
slides to present the
content of this paper.
So I give you the paper,
the agent reads and goes
to the PowerPoint and
organize the slides
and creates and gives you a
presentation of the paper.
Can you automate
some of the tasks
that we're doing on Excel,
going on the web, and so forth?
You can imagine a
lot of useful outcome
if you actually able to design
models that can do those tasks.
In this lecture, I'm going to be
focusing primarily on web agents
and give you a little
bit of overview
of what these models are,
how we evaluate these models.
And the idea here is that,
you have a basic language
model, some sort of
a foundation model.
Obviously, you need some form of
text understanding like in HTML,
and you also need to have
a very good understanding
of the visual information,
like the actual website itself.
So you can think of visual
encoding plus some form of text
understanding that goes
into large language model,
and that gives you some
form of web grounding,
that you can then use for
performing tasks on the web.
And there's been a lot of work.
I'm not going to list-- .
there's been a lot of work
in the last few years where
people are trying to understand
and trying to build systems
that can do these tasks.
Let me show you an example.
An example of a system
where I can say--
suppose I give the
task to my agent.
Get me to the page of a good
Thai restaurant in Pittsburgh.
It should have, at least,
200 reviews and 4.3 stars.
Pick the one with
the highest rating.
And this is what
the system does.
So it goes on Yelp.
It searches for
Thai restaurants.
It types in autonomously,
Thai restaurant.
It's then searching
through possible restaurant
in Pittsburgh.
It finds one of
these restaurants
which has 4.5 star rating.
It's a Pusadee Garden.
It's actually a pretty good
restaurant in Pittsburgh.
It's a good Thai restaurant.
Now it's complete.
Now, imagine I'm
asking it to say,
well, get me a
reservation at this
for two people at
the earliest date,
and use my name JY Koh, who
is the student who built this,
and the phone number.
And so the agent
goes on Google, finds
this particular restaurant,
looks at the dates,
looks at the next
available date,
and actually successfully
making a reservation.
And putting the phone
number, and then basically
stops because you need to get
a confirmation to actually book
something.
So it basically says, in
summary, the next section
I'll perform is stop.
Unable to proceed
without confirmation code
for further instructions to
complete the reservation.
So you have this notion of
the agent that takes tasks,
it generates a chain of
thoughts within thinking,
and then takes the action.
Or I can give the example
of, help me navigate
to the shirt that has on it.
So it goes on Amazon.
It's trying to basically
look for something similar,
and finds a shirt that
has something similar.
These are the examples that I
heavily cherry-picked out of--
I think that we've tried
maybe like 30 times.
And out of 30 times,
1 of them succeeded.
So that basically means that
these systems are not really
working very well at
this point, but it
has the potential
of give you a flavor
of what these systems can do.
I think in today's
world, OpenAI is
operating like-- sort of
moving in that direction.
It's one of the very strong
models that's out there.
So today I'm going to talk
about three different things.
I'm going to talk about
VisualWebArena, which
is a way of evaluating
multimodal agents on some
of the realistic visual tasks.
I'll talk about some of the
inference time algorithm, what
we call the Tree Search
Algorithm for large language
model agents, which allows
you to potentially do
interesting search,
apply interesting search
techniques to find necessary
information on the web.
And then the last part,
I'll talk a little bit
about some of the
way of scaling up
data for training these agents.
Because one of the aspects
of these agents in general
is the availability of data.
What can you do online, and how
can you get the data online?
So let's look at
the VisualWebArena.
One of the earlier versions
was developed by folks at CMU.
It was done by Shuyan
Zhou and Frank Xu.
They've introduced the
notion of WebArena,
which is a fairly realistic
environment at the moment.
It has popular
categories like shopping,
Reddit, and GitLab, which is
equivalent to Amazon and Reddit
and GitHub.
It's a self-hosted open
source essential environment,
which is a reimplementation
of the environment.
And the data comes
from real websites
from Amazon, Reddit, and GitHub.
And what's interesting
about this environment,
and I'll talk about
this, the tasks
are fairly easy for humans,
about 78% success rate,
but very difficult
for language models.
At that time, they
reported numbers like 14%.
The only problem with
this particular task
is that tasks are designed
to use just HTML source code.
And we found that a lot
of times, whenever you're
dealing with HTML
and JavaScript,
it's a very messy type
of representation.
Interactive
elements, when you're
interacting with
the environments,
they don't get displayed
correctly in HTML.
There is Java, a CSS code,
and it's very hard to process.
In the context length, HTML
pages can be fairly complex.
They can easily fill
up to 100,000 tokens,
if you're trying
to look at that.
And this is how it looks like.
You have this HTML-based
representation.
Spatial layout is also not
conveyed very well in HTML.
So it looks like just a
text only representation.
It's very difficult to deal
with just because HTML is messy.
So we've tried building
what we call VisualWebArena,
which is we try
to build and track
the process of
multimodal agents.
Agents that can actually
have visual grounding.
So we've designed these
visually-grounded tasks
to test the abilities
of these models.
And it's inspired by WebArena,
so we call it VisualWebArena.
And you have visual
inputs and outputs
that allows you to work with
unique and interesting--
and something that's real world.
And, again, we have
the environments
of what we call one-stop
shop, which is, essentially,
Amazon-like environment,
Reddit, and Osclass,
which is more like a
Craigslist type of environment,
the class field
type of environment.
So let me show you--
and then you can
think about that,
you have some representation,
I have some visual input,
and I ask you to
solve something that
actually requires
a visual grounding
and visual understanding.
So let me show you
some examples of this.
Let's say I ask--
I give you the task.
I ask you to find
this exact bike.
So I'm looking for this bike
that's listed for $300 to $500,
and post a comment offering
$10 less than the asking price.
And this is what
the agent has to do.
Again, it's a simulator.
It's a fully
self-hosted environment.
You go, you navigate,
you find this bike,
and then you basically
make a posting
by offering $10 less than
what the asking price is.
That's just one example.
And then, basically,
you've successfully
completed that task.
And I can imagine in
the future there's
going to be agents that's going
to be bargaining on your behalf,
and there's going to be agents
on the other side that's
going to be making
you counter offers.
Here's another example.
Let's say I ask you, buy the
cheapest color photo printer
and send it to Emily's
place as shown in the image.
And what you can see,
this image is upside down,
which makes it fairly
difficult for existing models
to look at this and
actually figure out
what the address should be.
So some of these
kind of tasks we
designed so that it wouldn't
be that easy for the models
to solve.
And so what the agent needs
to do, it needs to go,
it needs to find, it
needs to by price.
It gets the printer,
it adds to the cart,
then it goes and it starts
completing the address.
So it has pull-down menus.
So it looks fairly realistic.
And then you go and then
you place the order.
And when you end up in this
state, that particular state,
that basically means that
you've successfully accomplished
the task, right?
Again, just to reemphasize,
it's a simulation.
It's not actually doing
it on the real web.
It's a self-hosted environment.
Here's another one where
it requires you to jump
between two different websites.
You can ask, what's the
2022 total nominal GDP
of the area that produced most
sugarcane in the year of 2021
in billions?
And that's your landing page.
What's interesting here
is that you're essentially
asking the model to
understand the images.
Because if you look at the
year 2021, that's over here,
and you look, I
think in this case,
Asia produced more sugarcane
than Brazil or the other way
around.
Brazil produced more
sugarcane than Asia.
So you have to look
at these graphs
and understand which country
you should be looking at.
So if you zoom in,
you can say, OK, I
think that was Asia that
produced more sugarcane.
So you have to go on Wikipedia
and then find the answer.
And the answer is
339 trillion GDP.
So you can see that you have
to have this visual grounding.
You have to understand images.
You have to understand graphs
to solve some of these tasks.
So the way that the
environment is represented,
we can think of this environment
as a POMDP environment.
So it is partially observable
Markov decision process.
So you have states, you
have actions, observations,
and transition function.
And so for those of you who've
worked in reinforcement learning
or who have been dealing
with Markov decision, MDPs,
that should be familiar.
And that was the goal to design
the environment in such a way
that it becomes an MDP so
that you can potentially
train your favorite
reinforcement learning
algorithms on this.
So the environment
itself have observations,
whether it's an HTML, whether
it's the visual representation,
like the actual website
itself, and something
that we call the
accessibility tree, which
is a cleaned up
representation of HTML.
You have a set of actions.
And the set of actions is
actually a fairly diverse set
of actions.
You can click on a
particular element.
You can hover over a
This is an interesting one.
You can type in a
particular element and text.
So you can think, it's not
just a set of discrete actions.
Basically, you can
type in whatever,
if you're searching
for something
or you're feeling certain boxes.
You can have a new tab, so
you can jump to a new website.
You can focus on
a particular tab.
You can close the tab.
You can go a particular URL.
You can go forward, go
backwards, scroll up,
scroll down.
And then you have an action
called stop and then answer.
Stop is the action where the
model basically says, OK, I've
solved the task, stop, and then
I give you the final answer.
In this particular
environment, you
have deterministic
transition function.
You have the state that
generates the HTML page.
And given the state
and an action,
you generate the next state.
And the next state generation
is actually deterministic.
Basically meaning that if
you want a particular website
and you click on a particular
element or you type something,
there is only one--
there is no stochasticity so
gets you to the next state.
And we also defined
the reward functions.
And the reward
function is primarily
to evaluate when you've
successfully solved a task.
So it's a fairly
sparse reward signal
that we get in this environment.
But let me show
you-- just walk you
through what the model
actually needs to do here.
So what the model
needs to do is it
has to start on the home page.
So here you're trying to
find the cheapest printer.
And you have to
navigate to the printer
category in terms of the
actions that you need to take.
Then you have to sort
by descending order.
So if you click Sort by Price.
Then you click on the
cheapest color printer.
So you have to choose
what's the cheapest one.
So you have to understand how
much each printer cost and you
have to choose the cheapest one.
Then you have to add it
to the shopping cart.
That's another step.
You have to proceed to checkout.
Then you have to
fill in the form
correctly with the information
given to you in this image,
and then you have
to place the order.
So if you look at the
entire trajectory here,
it's a fairly
complex trajectory.
The model has to reason about
what it's seeing on the web.
It has to understand what
I mean by the cheapest,
so it has to have a
notion of sorting.
Then it has to really understand
good multimodal abilities
to understand what I'm
seeing in the images.
What's the edges?
And they have to go in
and fill in the address
with the right information.
So if you look at it, it's not a
very trivial task to accomplish.
And that's just one
of a thousand tasks
that we've designed.
So in terms of the distribution
of tasks across the websites,
we've looked at how
difficult those tasks are.
I think we have
950 tasks in total,
close to a thousand tasks.
And you can see
about 15% are easy.
Basically what that
means is that it's
easy in terms of
reasoning difficulty,
and easy in terms of
visually understanding
what I'm asking you.
Basically means you have
to do only a few clicks
to actually solve the task.
And then you have this corner
here, which is fairly difficult.
Reasoning difficulty,
so I really
have to understand what
I'm seeing in the image,
and visual difficulty--
and reasoning
difficulty basically
means that I have to
click on a lot of things
and explore to successfully
accomplish this particular task.
So in this particular
environment,
you can actually split
and try to understand,
is it my visual
models are missing,
or is it my
reasoning is missing?
Here's how we're evaluating
in this environment.
So we have execution-based
evaluation.
So, for example, a lot of times,
we want to find the exact match.
So if I'm asking
the question, what's
the ISIN number of
the company that
occupies the largest portion
of Warren Buffett portfolio?
Then I go to Wikipedia, I find
Warren Buffett's portfolio,
and then I get the
information, and I
need to get this exact number.
Sometimes if I
said, add something
like that to the man's wear--
whatever this man is
wearing to my wish list,
then I find something and
I basically have visual QA.
Is this a polo shirt, yes or
no, is this a green shirt,
and so forth.
And then you have--
sometimes when you're looking
for something, you say, it
has to include above 200,
or below 30, above 20,000,
below 30,000, and so forth.
So you can have these
verifiers that once I give you
the final states, I can
actually run these verifiers
and tell you, have you
solved the task or not?
And for a lot of these prompts,
there's only one solution.
Because the environment
is not the full internet,
it's fairly constrained,
but, at least, you
can verify whether your model
actually successfully solved
the task or not.
Now, when we think about
LLMs or visual language,
VLM agents, visual
language models,
the way to think about
this is the following.
One thing I can do is
I can look at the HTML
and try to use that as a
representation into my LLM.
It's also cluttered with a lot
of unnecessary information.
It has a long and
confusing context.
There's been a lot of work with
people doing markups, where
they're trying to identify
the relevant parts of the HTML
and trying to use that.
Another representation
is to use something
that's called
Set-of-Marks, which
is simplified representations.
So what it does is it
basically puts bounding boxes
around elements, around
clickable elements.
So whether I can click
on certain elements
or not, and that's something
that you can get from any HTML.
So that Set-of-Marks
representation
is something that you can do.
Both of these
representations have
advantages and disadvantages.
Set-of-Marks is useful
because, actually, visually,
I understand what I'm
seeing in the image
and what I can click on.
But it's also a very cluttered
type of representation.
And there is a third
type of representation
that people are now
beginning to use,
which is coordinate-based
representation,
where I'm just trying to
predict the coordinate of where
I need to click.
So ultimately,
it's probably going
to be a combination
of both HTML,
Set-of-Marks some kind of
coordinate-based representation.
And the way you can think about
these set of representation
is that if, let's say, I
have a regional web page,
I can use the Set-of-Marks
representation,
so I can put the bounding
boxes and have IDs for each box
and have some representation of
what each box is actually doing,
and perhaps have some form
of captioning of each image.
So I have this
Set-of-Marks elements
in the text, as well as the
actual visual representation.
And if I say, if I'm
trying to find this post,
navigate to the
comment section of it,
then you pass it to the
LLM or the LLM agent,
and then the agent actually
executes a precise action
to do next.
For example, I want to
click on Element ID 31,
and Element ID 31 is one
of the elements here.
And so, again, the way that we
typically have a representation.
I have a goal.
I get an observation.
I had represented
using Set-of-Marks.
That goes to the multimodal
large language models, both
the text and the image
as well as the goal,
and the model generates
a chain of thoughts.
So in this case,
it would generate--
let's think step by step.
The objective is to navigate
to the food, the post,
and so forth.
To navigate to this
listing, I need
to click on the comment link
associated with the sushi.
In summary, my next
action will be--
I'll perform action, click 34.
And, again, that's the
action that you're clicking.
So that's one particular action
that the model is taking.
And then it goes--
once you click on that
particular element,
the simulator will go to the
next web page, the next state,
and then you repeat
this process.
And here, again, the action is
you take a particular action
from the list of actions
that I've mentioned before.
Now, if I look at
baseline models
and try to understand which
models are working well
and which models are
not, what's interesting
is that, if I only use text
only-based representation,
then I hit something
like 90% accuracy.
If I use text plus
caption, so if I
caption any visual
information, any images
that I have on the web
pages, you have improvement.
If I actually try to
use multimodal model,
you get further improvement.
If I use Set-of-Marks
representation,
like, I understand clickable
elements and what I can do,
you get a little bit
of improvement as well.
So you go from 9% to
something like 18%.
And then you get human
level performance,
and the human level performance
hits close to, in this case,
for VisualWebArena, it
was hitting something
like 85%, 86% accuracy.
So there is a big
gap between what
people are capable of doing it
and what existing models are
capable of doing.
This was interesting.
The way that we've
collected the data is we
actually asked students at
CMU to solve these tasks.
We give them the prompts,
we give them the tasks,
we give them the
environment, and they just
interact with the environment,
and then they end in the state,
and then we evaluate using
our execution-based evaluation
whether they successfully
solved the task.
What's interesting
is that we found
that humans were not at 100%.
And what's interesting, a lot
of mistakes that people make
are silly mistakes.
So, for example, if I
ask you to find the--
if I ask you to say, well,
find me the cheapest bicycle
that has these specific
constraints or these conditions.
I want it to be black.
I want it to be of this color.
I want it to be
less than $2,000.
Go find me the cheapest bike.
What people tend
to do, people tend
to go through the
simulator, they
look at-- they find one bike,
they find a second bike,
and then they
basically say, OK, I'm
tired of looking
for anything else.
So I have two bicycles.
I take the cheapest
one and say, I'm done.
Whereas, actually,
there are 10 bicycles
that satisfy the constraints.
So people are just not very good
at information-seeking tasks.
Or, at least, we didn't
pay students enough.
We gave them pizza to go and
spend more than a few minutes
to solve these tasks.
So majority of the
information-seeking task
is where people were
not really good at.
And sometimes people
were a little bit--
They would solve the task,
but they would forget
to click on Place the order.
So they would solve the task,
they would add to the cart,
they find the right
thing, but they forget
to click on Place the order.
And if they forget
to place the order,
then our system basically
says that, well, you
haven't solved it
because you actually
haven't bought the item.
And so this is an
interesting part
because I think that
agentic systems should
be able to solve these tasks.
Agentic system should be
much better at information
seeking and finding
the information
just because it requires
less cognitive load,
whereas people are not
very good at doing that.
If I look at trying
to understand where
we are with these
models, you can
see that Llama, the
older versions of Llama,
they all were really bad.
If I have accessibility
tree plus captions,
a lot of these models
would go higher.
And then once I
have multimodals,
you have much better
representation.
And then once I have the
multimodal models, at that time,
looking at Gemini
Pro and GPT-4, I
think GPT-4 now hits
something like 90%
So these models do climb,
they do better, but they still
far below what people can do.
Even the best models
today are sitting
around 20% accuracy in terms
of solving these tasks.
And here's one example
I wanted to show you.
It's an interesting example
where the GPT model was
able to successfully solve it.
I ask you, I don't like
the author of this image
from the posts,
one of the posts.
Can you help me block them?
And the engine
would actually go,
it would click on the right
things, it would find the post,
it would go to the settings,
and through executing
multiple clicks,
it would actually
block a specific user,
just as an example.
You give it this
instruction, and the model
would actually go and do that.
And this has this
notion of-- that I'd
like to think about web
agent architectures,
and I'll make that reference
later on for physical agents.
But you can think about
these sort of architectures
where you observe some
input, say, a web page, you
do some form of parsing
of the web page,
whether it's visual
and HTML or some kind
of compressed representation of
HTML plus visual understanding.
You have an objective.
And the objective is
what I need to do,
and a lot of times, what a
lot of these models would do
is they would generate
a high-level plan.
They would generate a
plan of how to execute,
how you should proceed
to solve the task.
And then you execute
the low-level actions,
which is clicking on
a specific element.
And that goes in loop.
You can define the
high-level plan.
You can execute the
low-level action up
until you hit a stop
action, which basically
means that the agent is done.
I think I've solved the task.
And you can think of
planning as a system.
There's been some
work on building
these hierarchical systems
where, for example, step 1,
I can say, navigate me
to a particular category.
Step 2, I want to sort based
on the rating of that category.
And that would be two low-level
actions you're selecting
and then you're sorting.
And then maybe you
select an item under $20,
and then maybe you're
buying a selected item.
You need to buy it, and then
three low-level actions,
you add to the cart, you
proceed to the checkout,
and you do shipping.
So there is some sort
of work right now
that's trying to have the
planning model that actually
plans what you need to do
and then you execute those.
So VisualWebArena,
we think of it
as a step towards building
general purpose agents.
It's a simulator.
So you can evaluate
those models.
Tasks that we
designed are not very
consequential at this point.
They don't really represent
significant economic value
at this point.
And we've designed these
tasks to be simpler
because the current
large language model
agents or AI agents do not
even do well on these tasks.
The gap is still
fairly significant.
And the long-term
question is, can we
automate productive,
economically valuable tasks?
One of the interesting
failure modes
that we see these in models--
and, again, we're fixing those.
A lot of that progresses as the
models become better and better.
But one of the things
that we're seeing
is this notion of long horizon
reasoning and planning.
So models sometimes oscillate
between two web pages,
or sometimes they
get stuck in a loop.
So it's, I'm trying to do
something, I go to this web page
and then I go back and then
I go forward and I go back.
So there's this notion
of persistent memory.
A lot of times,
memory is missing,
so good representation of what
I've done so far is missing.
Of course, I can concatenate
every single web page
I visited with
every single HTML,
but that becomes
fairly cumbersome.
You need to have a good
persistent representation
of the memory.
A lot of times,
models would correctly
start on performing tasks,
and then undoing them.
I don't know why.
It just basically means they
don't have very good reasoning
abilities.
And a lot of times, agents tend
to stop exploration execution
too early.
So instead of exploring what
are the possibilities there,
they actually try to do
something, and then you stop
and you basically execute.
The stop action says like,
I can't solve the task.
I'm not seeing how I
can solve the task.
And there's also some
failures in visual processing.
So sometimes you can
click on the wrong items,
identifying specific items
in complex web pages.
There is also-- they lack a
little bit of spatial reasoning.
If you're asking
the question, what
are the prices of
products in the first row?
You have to understand
what the first row is,
what the second row, and
what's the middle row.
So certain spatial
understanding is missing,
but I think those
things will potentially
get better and better as we
can get the data for training
these models.
So what we need to do,
we need to do a lot more
to close the gap.
Definitely, reasoning and
planning over long horizons.
I'll talk a little
bit about this,
but that's one of the
key failure modes.
We also need to allow
agents to search.
You can think of it as
executing and coordinating
multiple instances in parallel,
and asking for clarifications
and confirmations.
So a lot of times,
search is actually--
you can think of it as test
time inference technique.
Basically tries to explore
possibilities to figure out
what's the right way
to solve the task.
And asking for
clarification, this
is where uncertainty
estimation comes in.
It's also fairly challenging
where, basically, the model
has to understand
that it's confused,
and then it has to
go and ask humans
for clarifications or guidance.
And, obviously, you need strong
visual language code models.
And also, identifying
appropriate levels
of abstractions
for agents like, do
you rely on screenshots,
what you are seeing visually?
Do you rely on HTML, or
maybe you rely on APIs?
There's a lot of websites
that would have APIs.
So maybe instead of actually
going through the web,
you actually go
through API calls.
And, again, I think that
multimodal models here
becomes very important because
a lot of real-world tasks
will require some form
of visual grounding.
So, for example, if you're
interacting with PowerPoint,
if you're interacting with
Photoshop, a lot of it-- yes,
you can do it through
API, but a lot of things
are also done through
visual grounding
and visual understanding.
So we definitely need to
train and build stronger
visual language models.
So that gives me this
notion of VisualWebArena,
which is the environment that
we use for doing evaluation.
Now, let's talk
about that research.
Or we can think of it as,
again, test time inference.
One interesting thing about
agentic agents in general
is that you have this notion of
exponential error compounding.
So, for example, if your
model accurately can--
can be accurate at one
step prediction at 90%,
then if you're
executing 30 actions,
then your accuracy
goes down to 4%.
So you basically need to
be very, very accurate.
So you need to be very precise
in terms of executing each step
in order to be able to
successfully-- solving
long horizon tasks.
And that's pretty
well-known, and any time
you have sequential
decision making process,
you have this issue.
The errors do
compound over time,
which makes it a very,
very difficult task.
So what happens here?
Well, local decisions have
global consequences So,
for example, let's say
I ask you the question,
add coconut milk to my cart.
Well, I can click
on Element ID 31
and that gives me
to the next state,
or maybe I can click
Element ID 24 that
gets me to the next
state, and then so forth.
So it's different choices.
There is a lot of action.
And the action space could
be exponential especially
if I'm doing searching as well.
So I can type text.
And so you can imagine
that each one of these
leads to a trajectory.
Once I execute the
trajectory, then potentially
I can evaluate which one is
right, which one is wrong.
And let's say, basically, this
state gives me the right outcome
and all the other states don't.
And especially if
you're executing
actions, 30 or 40 or 50 actions,
that becomes very challenging.
And if you have a policy
right now that-- you
can think of VLM as your
policy that basically predicts
the probability 0.5,
you should click on
this action, and
probability 0.1,
you should click on this
action, then, obviously,
finding the correct path is
going to be very difficult.
So you basically
have to-- you have
to be able to explore the
environment very efficiently
in this exponential space.
Now, one of the things that
turns out to work okay-ish,
or, at least, is a first
step, is doing search
by repeated sampling.
It's a very simple idea.
Very easy idea.
You sample action
from your model
until you hit the stop action.
So let's say you
sample this path.
And then you evaluate
the resulting trajectory.
So you look at the
trajectory and you can say,
have you solved the task or
did you not solve the task?
If you have verifiers
that can tell you
that you solved
the task, then you
know whether it's
success or not success.
And if it's a not
success, then you repeat.
This would be an
instance of what's
called rejection sampling.
You generate the trajectory,
you look at the outcome,
and if you didn't solve it, you
generate another trajectory.
This is a very simplistic way
called rejection sampling.
You basically sample until
you hit the right answer.
It's fairly inefficient, but
it's surprising that a lot
of work that's happening
right now, for example,
in the space of reasoning,
models like 01, 03 or Deep Seek,
they are essentially
doing exactly this.
They're essentially
doing rejection sampling.
I give you the math problem.
I start generating
thinking tokens up
until I get the right answer.
And so I start with
simpler prompts,
I generate sometimes right
answer, sometimes wrong answers.
I use reinforcement learning
to reinforce positive and then
dereinforce negative,
and start scaling it up.
So the simple idea
of rejection sampling
is essentially what's
driving a lot of innovation
right now in reasoning
capabilities.
Which is amazing and was
very surprising to me
that it actually works.
So we've started looking at
exactly the same problem.
But, for us, in this
particular domain,
it's not that you can
generate thinking tokens
and then you basically
get the answer here.
Here you actually have
to execute actions
in the environment
and you change
the state of the environment.
Which makes it much
more difficult.
So here you do
rejection sampling
and hopefully at some point
you'll hit the right answer.
What happens is that repeated
sampling tends to help.
So here is the
number of 10 runs.
And this is what
we call pass at 10.
Which basically
means that if you're
running your model
10 times, in terms
of-- you hit like 15%
probability of getting
the right answer.
So the more you
sample, the probability
that you'll hit the right
answer among these samples
is increasing, and that's
what this graph is showing.
And, however, the space
is exponentially large.
So can we guide
this exploration?
And the key idea here is
to apply the value function
to intermediate nodes.
It's a very old idea, but
you can apply it, actually,
in this space as well.
So how does this work?
So the idea is to, basically,
do a form of a best-first search
algorithm with a few tweaks.
So what are the ingredients
of the algorithm?
So the baseline agent
proposes actions.
The baseline agent
actually says, OK,
here's two actions
that I can take.
These are the most
probable action
according to the
base model, according
to your original policy.
You have to have a way to
backtrack in the environment.
So that basically means
that, in this state,
you want to be able to
backtrack to the original state.
This is sometimes
difficult to do, especially
in web environments
because some actions,
you can't backtrack from,
and these actions that we
call destructive actions.
If I place the order, I can't
just go back and unplace it.
That's just one example.
So we'll talk a
little bit about this.
And then you also have
to have a value function.
You can think of a
value function that
takes the input, whatever
your presentation is, plus
it takes a sequence of previous
observations or previous steps
and outputs a score.
And you can think a value
function essentially
looking at the expected
value, expected reward.
In our settings, think of it as
the probability of successfully
solving the task.
So it's a number between
0 and 1 that basically
says, if I'm in this state
and my value function is 0.5,
then the probability of
me succeeding is 50%.
And if the value
function in this state
is 0.3, then the probability
of me succeeding is 30%.
So maybe this state is
better than this state.
So you have to have a
good value function,
and these are values
that you can associate.
And what we've done in this
work is we're basically
using LLM as a judge.
So in this case,
you take a GPT-4o,
you take the full trace,
the full trajectory,
and you're asking
the model to say
how good the state is in terms
of solving a particular task.
So there's a way to use
this LLM as a judge.
There's a few tricks
of self-consistency
that you can use.
But essentially, you can just
use a large language model
as a judge to judge each state.
Ultimately, I do believe that
the next-generation models will
create their own
value functions.
You'll train your own value
function that basically
will guide this exploration.
OK.
So how does this work?
Let's say that I
give you a task.
The task construction
is, can you
add this and the other canned
fruit of the same brand
that looks like this,
but red instead of brown
to the comparison page?
So how does this work?
Well, you take the action,
and then at this point
you have three possible
actions to take.
They all have a
probability-- they all have
the value function of 0.45.
So you pick one of
them, you proceed,
and then you go to the
next kind of state,
and your value
function decreases.
So you basically say,
OK, I'm actually-- maybe
I'm on the wrong path
to solving this task.
And then I backtrack and
I take another action.
So I backtrack to
the previous state,
and I take the other action.
And let's say here I go in,
my probability increases.
I go in, my
probability increases.
And then I hit a
particular state
where I'm not actually
going to solve
this task because my
value of the state
is actually pretty
small because I ended up
in a very wrong state.
So then I have to be able to
backtrack again from this state.
I have to be able to backtrack
back to the original state,
and then go and, again,
take the next states,
and then if it's bad, backtrack
and eventually solve the task.
So you can see that
it's more expensive,
there are different
ways of exploring,
but the key here that drives
a lot of this exploration
is the value of the state.
Which basically is telling you
how good the particular state is
in terms of solving the task.
And you can spot the errors
early on and say, no, no, no,
backtrack and restart again.
So it's a little bit better
than just doing random rejection
sampling because here you're
doing guided exploration.
It's very similar to-- some of
you are familiar with AlphaGo
setting, right?
Where you basically have
an environment where
you have a value of
the state and then
you try to explore
which actions to take,
and you evaluate those states
given the value function
that you have.
And so if we look at the
results, what we found
is that, for Web Arena, there
is pretty decent improvement
in terms of the ability
to solve these tasks.
For the VisualWebArena, we
also see quite reasonable
improvements by using
this exploration.
It's more expensive.
And so we do see that
these search at test time
actually improves model's
ability to solve the task,
or, at least, to solve
some of the tasks.
You can still see that
we're still very far away
from hitting 90% accuracy.
But nonetheless, it's
actually a progress, where
we're progressively improving.
And we do see that if you
look at the success rate,
c 0 indicates no search.
And then the more node
expansions you have,
the better your performances.
And then you can also
look at the success rate
relative to how
you want to expand.
Do you control the depth
versus the breadth,
and, again, how much you
want to explore versus
what's the branching factor?
And then if we keep exploring
and doing the branching,
then the accuracy tends to go
up just because the model is
able to explore possible
different possibilities
or different environments.
A lot of times what we
see in these settings
is that, if I ask it to
buy a blue polo shirt,
if you don't do the search,
the model, let's say,
goes and let's say it
clicks on the wrong thing,
and it ends up on a web page
that only has blue polo shirts.
So you're asking
black polo shirt
and gives you blue polo shirts.
And then the model
says, well, there
are no black polo
shirts because I'm only
seeing blue polo shirts.
I can't solve the task.
Done.
And, obviously, this
is the case that if you
can backtrack and explore, you
will find the right answer.
So this notion of
search actually
becomes fairly
important and such.
And we also found that
having a good value function
is essential.
There is still a lot of headroom
for improving the base policy.
Obviously, your base
policy has to be good.
It can't just take
random actions.
If your base policy is--
if your base model is
actually pretty weak,
then you'll just be
taking random actions
and there's only that much
you can do with exploration,
but you need to improve both.
And you can see, if you use
different value functions,
then the performance
actually improves.
With no search, if you say
lava, which is a weaker version,
you get the improvement.
If you use something for all
type of models, then you have--
so if you have a
better value function,
kind of looks at
the full trajectory,
then you have improvements
in performance.
And the interesting
thing is that using
LLM as a judge, judging whether
the trajectory is good or bad,
is much easier than predicting
what the next action
you should take or what the
next element you should click on
and what you should
be searching on.
And so that's why starting--
using value function as an LLM,
initially, I think it's
a reasonable thing to do,
but, obviously, you want
to be able to improve this.
Here's just some examples.
You can basically say, I
recall seeing this exact item
on the side.
Help me find the most
recent post of it.
I recall seeing it in either
collectibles or antiques
section.
So the models would go
to the starting state,
it would explore, and
then eventually find
that particular posting.
Or this one where I can
say, hey, I like this.
I need something like
this in my apartment.
Can you add one to my wish list?
So the model have to
go, it has to search
through different environments,
find this specific item,
and add it to your wish list.
It would be great if you
have something like that.
You take a picture of
something, and you basically
tell your agent, hey, go
and find it on Amazon,
Best Buy, or wherever, get
me the best price for this,
and see where I can buy it.
Just as an example.
Now, in terms of
limitations of this,
well, search is pretty slow.
So you, obviously, need a fast
way of doing backtracking.
We did the backtracking
in a relatively naive way.
You store all actions
in a queue and then
take them again to get
to the original state.
So if you've taking
20 actions, you
store what you've done so
far, and then to go back,
you rerun that again.
So it's not very
efficient what we've done.
I think it's just requires
infrastructure work.
And the other interesting
piece is dealing
with destructive actions.
Certain things on the web
are very difficult to undo.
Especially if you're
operating on the real web
for testing these models.
You can't order the item
and then unorder it.
It's not like you can order the
item, and then your model says,
you know what, that was
actually the wrong order.
Let's try ordering
something else.
You can't do that.
And so the other thing that
you can't, unfortunately,
do in the real web
is it's very hard
to do some form of
learning in the real web.
Because anything that changes
the state of the environment
is actually fairly difficult.
I can't go on the United
and start booking flights from
Pittsburgh to San Francisco
to learn how to
book the flights.
Because if I'm exploring
and I'm saying,
why don't I click here, well,
maybe I should click here,
and then maybe I should
try to book this flight
and then maybe it's wrong and
try to book this other flight.
And so it becomes a
little bit tricky to do
because, essentially,
United will block you.
Or United will
basically say, oh,
there's so many
people are trying
to book flights from
Pittsburgh to San Francisco.
Maybe we should
increase the prices.
So you have to be careful
how you're actually
operating in the real world.
So what's the current work?
Obviously, search as a
policy improvement function.
You can use search as a way
of finding the correct trace
or the correct trajectory.
And you can use this potentially
either in reinforcement
type of learning algorithm
or actually in SFT
to try to fine-tuning this.
Improving value
function by fine-tuning
instead of prompting.
So if you can improve the value
function by using Monte Carlo
rollouts, you can do that.
Obviously, exploring tradeoffs
between improving baseline
agent, how much your
base model has to be,
versus how much more search you
have to do at inference time.
And today we see this
notion of test time
inference scaling loss where,
well, if I do search for more,
I can probably get
a better answer.
And I think that
it's true, but it's--
both models need to improve.
Your base model
needs to be better,
and also search needs
to be more efficient.
And, obviously, one of
the biggest questions,
if we don't have a
simulator of the web
environment, how can we
collect data at scale?
And that's one of the
interesting problems
that we also started
looking at, what can we do
and how we can collect
the data at scale?
Because the interesting thing
about agentic models in general
is that it's the kind of
data that's very difficult
to find on the web.
So what we see with
existing LLMs is
that I can crawl the web, I
can scrape images and HTML,
and then I can pre-train
these models just doing
the next token prediction.
For agentic work,
it's very difficult.
It's very difficult for
me to say, hey, give me
a whole bunch of
examples and show me
how I should be booking
my flight from Pittsburgh
to San Francisco.
Or show me, in
this setting, like,
hey, I like something like this.
Add me to my wish list.
It's not like you can find
a lot of these examples
on the web of examples
of people showing you
how to solve these tasks.
So this notion of giving the
task and the full trajectory
of how you should take
actions and solve the task
is actually very limited
data that we have today.
In fact, we don't
have any of that data.
A lot of companies, they're
essentially collecting this data
in-house by asking people
to solve these tasks
and do massive annotations.
So the question for
us was, how can we
collect the data at scale?
And that gives me
to the third point,
which is, how can we,
at least, try thinking
about what we can do here?
So as I've mentioned
before, agents
suffer from a data problem.
And you can see the gap
is still pretty big.
And when we think about LLMs,
the way that we're training them
today, a lot of times
they're often trained online.
I just collect a bunch of
data, and then I deploy them
as zero-shots as agents.
And then I collect
a lot of data,
I do some form of
supervised fine-tuning,
at least, that's what's
happening in academia,
and then I try to deploy
them and see how they work.
The question is, can we
somehow go on the real web
and generate synthetic tasks to
unlock this large-scale training
of agents?
And the question is, how can
we, again, get these models
to generate something synthetic
and actually build something
that we can train on
and improve our edges
without human intervention, or
without actually task generated
by humans?
Because it's fairly expensive to
ask humans to generate or create
those tasks.
So one of the things that
we've been trying to build
is we've been trying to
build this internet scale
training for agents that
we call InSTA, which is--
the idea here is, with
using Llama models,
to generate and verify
synthetic agentic tasks.
So we're thinking
about three stages.
There is a task
generation stage.
For example, I can
ask the model to say,
find me a code base for
generating images with Flux.1.
That's the first task.
I'll show you examples
of how we can do that.
The second task is evaluation.
Actually, executing this
task, and then trying
to see whether the
model solved the task.
And then the third step
is actually collection--
basically, collecting
it at scale.
But you can think
of this environment
is that the model
proposes tasks,
the model executes those
tasks, the model then evaluates
those tasks, and then if
it's successfully it says,
yeah, I propose the task.
I executed this task on
the real web, I evaluated,
I think I've solved the task.
Then that becomes a very useful
data for training our agents.
So let's see how we can do.
So, for example,
given the web domain,
for example, there's
a domain, just
random domain, Mersey Ferries,
it's a website in the UK,
and we can ask the
system to propose
realistic tasks that
an average user could
complete in one session.
So there's a certain
system prompt
that we're asking the
model to generate the task.
And what's interesting is that
if you look at Llama-70B-3.1,
I think we're also
training on Llama 3.3,
which is actually better,
has better results,
so these models
continue improving.
So if I ask the
model to describe,
what is this website about,
it's actually pretty good.
It says, well, this
particular website
is the official website for
famous Mersey Ferries service
in Liverpool,
England, and so forth.
Certain things you can do.
You can plan a journey.
You can book tickets
and gives you
ideas of what you can
do with this website.
And so that gave
us this notion of,
if the model understands
what this website is about,
maybe I can ask it to
actually generate the task.
And what we found is
that we can scale it
across many, many different
websites from Common Crawl.
I think we started with
about a million websites,
and we started thinking
about what kind of tasks
these models can generate.
And a lot of tasks
actually involve
some form of information
retrieval, some sort of search.
You're finding the right
ticket information.
You're finding
booking-- opening hours.
You find specific information
on a particular topic.
But crucially, we do not modify
the state of the internet.
So that was one of
the settings for us,
where we asking the
model to come up
with a task that don't modify
the state of the environment.
So, for example, booking
something, we can do.
Or clicking on something that
actually changes the state
of the environment, we can do.
This specifically was done to
avoid any sort of complications
of us being blocked.
And as I mentioned
before, we can't
go on united.com or
booking.com and start
running a lot of tasks, booking
a lot of hotels randomly.
So we can only navigate
to these websites,
but we actually cannot change
the state of the environment.
What we found is that a lot of
tasks that the models actually
come up with are
diverse, and many require
multiple steps of reasoning.
So, for example, if I
go to fonts.adobe.com,
some of the generated
task is browse fonts
suitable for a children's book.
So you have to understand
what makes a font
suitable for a children's book.
A lot of tasks can identify
facts that's likely to contain.
So, for example, if I'm
going to ancient-symbols.com,
the generated task would be,
look up the meaning of the word
Om symbol in ancient cultures.
You have to go on this
website, this is the task,
and I have to crawl
through this website
to actually find
what's the meaning
of that particular symbol.
Or, I can go to this particular
obscure Scottish design studio
and ask, view the
latest fabric designs
by this particular studio.
So I end up on
this website and I
have to find the latest
designs, fabric designs.
And this is how it looks like.
I actually have to end up
on this particular web page
because that lists the
latest fabric designs
by that particular studio.
So these tasks are
grounded even for sites
in the tail of the
data distributions.
So these are-- we wanted
to go for breadth,
not necessarily to only cover
a hundred most commonly visited
websites, but also
going to these--
which gives us the diversity
of the environments
and different websites and
different generated tasks.
So that's the first step,
try to generate the tasks.
Now, the second
state is, OK, how
do we know when these
tasks are solved?
And that gives us the
task evaluation part.
And the way we do
this is we basically
say, OK, if we're given
the task, generate a task,
we can execute this task
using the current model.
Let's say you have a GPT model
or you have your Llama model,
in this case, it was a Llama
model that we're using,
you observe a
sequence of actions
and the last
observation, and you now
estimate the probability
of a task being successful.
So you're basically
asking the model--
given the last state in
the sequence of actions,
you're asking it to estimate
the probability of the success.
This is, again, the same
idea as using large language
model as a judge.
Here we're actually evaluating
the full trajectory,
but you can think of it as--
in the previous part when we
were looking at the search,
we essentially we're
using the same piece,
but only evaluating
partial trajectories
to try to figure out
what we should explore
and what we shouldn't explore.
Here we're actually trying to
evaluate the full trajectory.
But, obviously, you can combine
search with this technique
as well.
So you can search around and
try to find the best outcome.
And you prompt Llama to rate
the confidence of the tasks
it solved from 0 to 1.
And what we found is that, for
example, out of 150,000 tasks,
about 15% are rated as success
with high confidence by Llama,
roughly 22,000 tasks.
We actually did verify how
good using Llama as a judge.
And I think that in terms of
the success, it was about 90%.
So, for example,
when the model says,
I'm pretty sure I've solved the
task, with human evaluations,
we're seeing close to 90%
accuracy among those ones.
So basically means,
whenever Llama
says, yes, I've solved
the task, 90% of the time,
it actually solved the
task, 10% of the time,
no, it didn't solve the task.
So these verifiers
are not perfect,
but they are pretty
decent in terms
of approximately telling you
whether you solved the task
or not.
So that gives you this notion of
showing that you've successfully
found the task, executed,
and then verified it.
Let me give you a
visual representation
of what that looks like.
So on a different
project, we have a project
where we're working
with ecologists
on identifying invasive plants
in different environments.
And we basically
thought, OK, let's
look at this website,
Invasive Plants Atlas,
and prompt the model
to generate a task
and see if the model
can solve the task.
So the model basically
generates a task,
find invasive plant species
native to North America.
So that's more like
information extraction.
And the agent response is to
find an invasive plant species
in North America.
I will first click
on link all species
to view the list of all species.
OK.
So it takes and, based
on this information,
it clicks on All Species.
And that's what the
action looks like.
It's a little JSON that you
have an action key click,
you have action
arguments that can go in,
and you have a target element
ID, the ID that you associated
with that particular click.
Then it basically says,
to find invasive plant
species native to
North America, I
will first click
on the link home
because it's trying
to go to the sources.
And it sort of misses the point
because there is a sources here.
But it actually
insists on going home
and then to find the sources.
So it misread, so it made
a mistake in this case.
Since the link to sources is
not on the current web page,
but it is, so it's
making a mistake,
I will first click on the Home
and go back to the main page.
So it goes back
to the main page,
and then it identifies
the sources.
So it clicks on the Sources.
It actually gets
to the right piece,
to find invasive plants
native to North America,
I will first click on the
A under the native range
taxonomic references.
So it execute pieces, and
it does clicks on that,
on the correct element.
And then once it gets
to the correct element,
it then basically says, I
need to sort based on US--
plants that are native to the
US, gets it in a JSON format,
and then gives you the answer.
Since the list is already
sorted by US nativity
by ascending order, that's it.
I can find the first like
165 plant species that
are native to North America.
So this gives you the list.
And the answer is, basically,
I give you the web page,
and I tell you, the first
165 plant species on the list
are invasive plant species
native to North America.
So in terms of me finding
information seeking,
again, this was a completely
synthetically generated task
where the model
proposed the task.
It's now executed the task,
even though it made a mistake,
and then it gave you the action.
And in this case, despite
reasoning, some of the reasoning
failures, because it
clicked on the wrong thing
but then it recovered, it
found the target information,
and in this case, Llama verifier
evaluates this trajectory
successfully with
confidence 1.0.
And, again, whenever it
does this verification,
it's about 90% accurate.
Maybe close to-- maybe
85%, 90% accurate
when we did the
studies, human studies.
So that gives you an interesting
synthetic generation.
Where you're proposing the task,
you're executing this task,
and then you verify, did
you solve the task or not?
And, again, only 14%
or 15% of the tasks
that the model proposed and
executes, only 15% of them,
the model basically says, yes,
I think I solved the task.
85% of them, you
can't solve the task.
But that's OK because it's
all done automatically.
There is no human
in the loop here.
Let me show you some
examples, other examples
of what the model does.
So here's the example.
Find me the opening hours
of La Sagrada Familia.
It's a fairly famous
church in Barcelona.
So it proposes a task,
it browses the web,
and it finds the answer.
So, again, this is the
task that it proposes.
It goes to the website.
It actually finds
the Sagrada Familia,
it clicks, it finds, and it
basically, from the table,
finds what the right answer is.
Well, find the information on
the European Union's climate
action policies.
So it goes to the European Union
Commission, it crawls the web,
and then this is a
success where it actually
finds the documents related
to the climate action progress
or climate action policies.
And, again, this tasks are
completely created by model
proposing what the task should
be, model executing this task,
and then the model verifying
whether it successfully
completed the task or not.
So we went through
these two stages.
And, again, I'm not saying
that that's a perfect setting.
I think that if you
incorporate search,
if you have better models,
and then you iterate it
multiple times, I think
the quality of generation
of these tasks could
improve substantially.
So let me talk a little bit
about the data collection.
So what happens with
the data collection?
Now we can scale up
the data collection.
So we've used the
Common Crawl PageRank
to find the most
important websites.
We start with the top
1 million web pages.
We filtered it down to
about 150,000 live websites
by filtering harmful content.
So we're prompting
the model so if we
think that there is harmful
content on the website,
we basically ignore it.
So we're about 97%,
actually, pretty high,
in terms of detecting and
filtering harmful content.
This is used using Llama models.
We are about 89% success
rate in generating
feasible tasks, and about
80%, so it's like 90%,
in generating feasible
tasks, which basically means
that when we're verifying
whether the task is successful
or not, we're 89%.
And 82% accuracy in judging
successful task completion.
Sorry, that's the one where--
82% whether the task is
successfully completed or not.
And, again, we went through
150,000 live websites,
and then we attempting it and
verifying it and creating data
based on whether we successfully
generate the task and whether we
successfully execute it
and then verified success.
What's interesting is that we
found that on toy-ish examples
and small examples,
Mind2Web, WebLINX.
These are some of the
data sets that people use.
We found that
training on synthetic
and human demonstration scale
faster than just training
on human demonstrations.
So actually, if you're mixing
what humans collected versus
if you're mixing synthetic and
humans, we can see improvements.
We also see that
adding synthetic data
improves step accuracy by
certain numbers, so that's good.
We also found that if you
only use human annotations,
human annotations do
struggle with generalization.
Because a lot of times what
actually ends up happening
is that with human
annotations, they're
typically done on a small subset
of highly-visited websites.
And the ability to generalize
to the tail of the distribution,
that's where synthetic data
really helps us because it can
help us generalize to the tail
of the distribution, where
it's very difficult for
humans to collect the data.
Obviously, the
ultimate choice would
be to get humans to
annotate the entire web.
That would be the
best because then we
can just do imitation learning.
But we do find that, the
ability to crawl the web
and look at this
tail distribution,
we do see improvements
in generalization.
Now, there are 385
million unique domains,
suggesting maybe another
1,000x more data that could be
available by scaling further.
We were constrained by
compute and academic resources
when we did this work.
And, of course, there
is also this notion
of moving towards online
reinforcement learning.
So you can think about settings
where you run this procedure.
You collect the synthetic data,
and then you update the model
and do it again.
So you can do it
in online fashion.
You crawl the web, you
generate these tasks,
you try to solve
some of these tasks,
you update the model
parameters, and do that again.
So if you have an online--
and that could be an online
reinforcement learning,
but done at scale, at
the internet scale,
I think these models would
improve significantly.
And, of course,
it's very difficult
to do that on the
real web because it's
very hard to change--
you can't change the
state of the environment.
So you have to be careful how
you're actually scaling it up
when you go to the real
world or the real web.
Let me just, in the
last 10 minutes and I'll
leave the room for
questions, I wanted
to point out that this
notion of agentic environment
is also applicable to
the physical agents
or robots in general, right?
So we've also-- very
parallel effort,
we basically thought,
OK, these AI agents have
the same notion whether
we're operating on the web
and taking actions on the
web, or whether we actually
have a physical agent, like
a robot that takes actions
in the real world, right?
So, for example, you can
think about observing
the data, which could be the
image plus maybe the depths.
You do some form of
semantic segmentation
to understand the environment.
You have an objective.
You generate a
high-level plan and then
you generate the
low-level actions
like interacting with
the actual environment.
So we have this work on
planning learning, what
we call plan, sequence, and
learn, where the idea is
a language model
basically gives you
a sequence of high-level
plan, what you need to do.
You have a sequencing
or parsing module
that basically understands the
environment, sequences this.
And then we have a
low-level action,
which we learn with
reinforcement learning, which
is a little policy that
actually learns how
to take a particular action.
So very much in
flavor, very similar
to what the web
agents are doing,
but now we're actually
interacting in the real world.
So, for example, a planning
module can say, OK, here's
the task.
Get me-- I'm trying to put the
silver nut on the silver peg
and the gold nut
on the gold peg,
and then give me the simple
plan to solve this task.
And so the LLM basically
produces a fairly simple task
of how I should solve it.
We have a sequencing model,
which looks at the observation.
There's a depth.
We do segmentation and a
little bit of projections,
so have some form
of 3D representation
of the environment.
And then it goes through
the inverse kinematic,
and we have a motion planner.
But you can think
of this as like,
again, understanding
the environment
and doing a little bit
of motion planning.
And then the low-level
action module actually
learns the local policy.
So here you have reinforcement
learning for interactions.
Kind of locally learning
how to interact with it.
Much like when you're clicking
on a particular element.
Here we're actually learning how
to control our joint angles so
that we can accomplish
a low-level task.
And so this is
how it looks like,
where a local model is
actually learning how to--
with reinforcement
learning, it's
actually learning how to
interact with the environment.
And so in the full pipeline,
very much in similar spirit,
you have a planning
model that plans high--
gives you a high-level plan.
For each high-level
plan, you're executing
this lower-level actions
where you basically
have pose estimation, motion
planning, a little bit
of reinforcement learning
to take the action.
And then you have this low-level
control that actually controls
low-level actions via
reinforcement learning,
and then you proceed.
And that's just the first
step, and you go to the next,
and then you go to the next,
and execute that according
to the plan, and so forth.
And we found that these sort
of models work reasonably well.
PSL solves about 25
long-horizon robotic tasks
across, in this case, four
benchmarks, with about 85%
success rate.
We also tried extending this
to the actual real environment.
So here is the--
I give it a task, put
mouse in the drawer.
So the model basically
generates the plan,
and, again, it looks
at the environment,
parses the environment, and
then executes low-level actions.
And it does a lot of
interesting things.
But the point I do
want to make here
is that, whether you're
operating in a virtual space
or whether you are operating
in the real-world space,
the ideas are fairly
similar across domains.
And so here, you can generalize
to new object, object
geometries, new categories.
And so we've never trained
on this particular--
for this particular
object, but you
can successfully complete it.
You can deal with multiple novel
objects with unseen receptacles.
So these models can
do reasonably well.
It's not perfect, by all means.
I think we're hitting success
rates about 80% to 90%.
But these models do generalize.
They can manipulate
deformable objects.
You don't observe them when
we're training these models
in the simulator, but
training in the simulator
does translate into
the real world.
OK.
Now, to summarize, we've
talked about VisualWebArena
as a benchmark for these
realistic tasks designed
to evaluate the capabilities of
autonomous multimodal agents.
We've talked about inference
time search algorithm,
which is designed to enhance the
capabilities of language models
for realistic web tasks, and
how we can do the search.
And there's a lot
of research that
needs to be done in that space.
And then we've talked
about the data pipeline
for large-scale generation
and verification
of these synthetic
tasks that the model can
create powered by Llama models.
And the interesting thing
about all of these settings
is that you can try to
generate these synthetic tasks.
You can use inference time
to generate something better.
You can use data
collection with humans,
and ultimately,
it's the combination
of all of these pieces
that will potentially
lead to models that
can work very well
in the real-world environments.
One last thing I
do want to mention
is that, AI safety
and robustness
becomes fairly
important, especially
in the age of
autonomous systems.
And what's essentially
happening today
is that these systems
are not-- first of all,
they're not very robust.
If I ask it to do some task,
sometimes it completes the task,
sometimes it doesn't.
And it's very
difficult-- like, if I
want to have a system that
books my flights as an example,
I don't want to have a system
that's only 80% correct.
I don't want a system that 80%
books the right stuff and 20%
doesn't book the right--
books the wrong planes for me.
That's unacceptable.
So having these agentic
capabilities that actually
are very good at executing
tasks and perhaps
asking for
clarification questions
so you have some model
in the loop becomes
very important research and very
important, which is missing--
I think that's missing today.
On AI safety, that's
another area of research.
Because a lot of times, these
agents are very brittle.
So you can actually
adversely modify them.
And so this is some work.
There's a lot more work that's
happening in this space.
But we found this one
interesting settings,
this was done on VisualWebArena,
where we basically change
the representation of images.
So you have a web page, on the
web page, you have your images,
and you change
your representation
of the images in such a way
that the captioning system, when
it captions it, actually
provides an instruction
to the language model of
what it should do next.
So we can hijack these
agents and basically say--
add the comment, looks
great, before providing
the next action.
So if the model ends
up on your web page,
instead of navigating
to the next one,
it will leave the
comment saying,
this is a terrific product,
and then go to the next one.
So you can force it to
generate, for example,
positive feedback for your
product so you can boost your--
a lot of agents or
people like your product.
So it's just it's a little
bit toy-ish at this point,
but it becomes fairly
important because you
don't want to have a system--
you want to have a system that's
robust to these
adversarial settings
where I can modify my
state in an adversarial way
so as to ask the model to take
a different action than it's
supposed to take.
And finally, this
is a funny example,
but I wanted to
mention, like, there's
a lot of work in the industry on
building these types of models.
Obviously, we want to have
systems that can look at the web
and do a lot of tasks on you.
But this was done by Claude
Anthropic's computer use.
And so it kind of-- they have
this funny thing where you say,
in one episode,
Claude accidentally
clicked to stop a long
running screen recording,
causing all footage to be lost,
and another clock suddenly
took a break from
our coding demo
and began to use photos of
Yellowstone National Park.
And the reason why
these models do that?
Because you have a sequence,
you have a set of actions.
And so if it's trying
to accomplish the task,
takes the wrong
action, then it--
once it takes the
wrong action and it
doesn't have the search
ability to understand,
I'm not actually--
I've taken the action that is
not consistent with my task,
then it's very hard for it
to backtrack potentially.
Once you're taking the action,
it's trying to take another
action, maybe it's
trying to recover,
and then basically cannot
recover back to the original
set.